### Contact

pradeepkumar.peddi@invesco.com

www.linkedin.com/in/peddipradeep (LinkedIn)

www.invesco.com (Company)

## Top Skills

Vendor Management Screening Requirements Analysis

## Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

Hindi

Telugu

### Honors-Awards

Outstanding Performance & Contribution to Talent Acquisition - Q4 2013 & Q1 2014

# Pradeep Kumar Peddi

Head of Talent Acquisition @ Invesco India Pvt. Ltd. Hyderabad

## Summary

Pradeep has around 16 Years of Experience in Staffing/Recruitment [Area of Expertise: Technology/Investment Services/ Support Function, Recruitment – Human Resources]

Pradeep is currently heading Talent Acquisition function for Invesco's Enterprise centers in India and responsible for Hiring Top talent for Information Technology, Investment, Investment Services and Support functions (Compliance, Finance, Finance & Accounting, Audit & Human Resources) teams. An experienced recruiting Professional with expertise in hiring for Product companies, setting up new teams and help startups build brand & hire.

Prior to joining Invesco, Pradeep was associated with HighRadius (Product Firm) and responsible for managing the Talent Acquisition team and delivering top talent for Information Technology & Operations Verticals into Financial Supply Chain Management domain.

## Experience

Invesco Ltd.
3 years 8 months

Head of Talent Acquisition March 2020 - Present (6 months)

Hyderabad, Telangana

India Talent Acquisition Manager March 2018 - March 2020 (2 years 1 month) Hyderabad Area, India

Asst. Manager, Talent Acquisition January 2017 - February 2018 (1 year 2 months) Hyderabad Managing the TA Function (Technology/Investment Services/Global Functional Support Services)

Reachout to me for careers into Information Technology, Investment, Investment Services and Support functions (Compliance, Finance, Finance & Accounting, Audit & Human Resources)

Contact information

Email ID: pradeepkumar.peddi@invesco.com

Invesco Hyderabad Pvt. Ltd
Team Lead, Talent Acquisition
August 2013 - December 2016 (3 years 5 months)

HighRadius (Product Development Company)
1 year 9 months

Talent Acquisition @ HighRadius July 2012 - July 2013 (1 year 1 month)

Managing end to end lateral recruitment operations for the service line Working with various business leaders to understand the hiring needs across technology areas for the BU and cascade to the team.

Build and manage strong sourcing, selection and networking capabilities to hire in a cost effective environment and efficient manner.

End to End involvement with the process, from sourcing, conducting interviews until candidate's on-boarding.

Sr. Recruiter - Recruitment November 2011 - June 2012 (8 months)

- Responsible for Delivery
- Direct Interaction with Line of Business at Onsite for Review Calls with data preparation, setting up Interviews, Hiring Approvals, etc.
- Have continuously been guiding LOB Partners on Indian Market for Hiring the Right Talent (On Skills available, Hiring Process, Notice Periods, Dropouts, etc)
- Won the Confidence of Business hiring key positions which were open for over 2 Quarters
- Successfully Hired across Functions and handling team of 4 recruiters.

Mobitec Consultant (I) Pvt. Ltd Asst Manager/Delivery Lead - Recruitment May 2008 - October 2011 (3 years 6 months)

 Responsible for End-to-End Recruitment life-cycle which involves Understanding the

Requisitions, Identifying Sourcing Channels, Conducting Hiring Events such as Walk-ins and Scheduled Interviews, Salary Negotiations, Documentations & Post-Offer follow-ups

- Coordinating with the Hiring Managers on their current requirements on weekly basis
- Screening and short listing resumes from sources like website, Jobsites like Naukri and Monster

as per the job specifications.

- Scheduling candidates for the interviews through different modes
- Releasing offers & follows up with the candidates till the joining date.
- Follow up the offered candidate till they join
- Negotiations, Liaising with Contractual Agencies
- · Maintenance of Recruitment Information Systems like
- · No. of Manpower Requisitions received.
- · No. of interviews scheduled.
- No. of candidates Selected/ Rejected.
- Administering technical and aptitude tests for the short listed candidates.
- Preparing the weekly status reports with respect to Job Requirements vs.
   Candidates in the Pool suitable for requirements log
- Interfacing with people at all levels, managing healthy work environment and inculcating bonded teamwork with high work ethics
- Recruited for technologies like Java, Dotnet, DWH, ERP's (Oracle Apps, peoplesoft, SAP), Oracle, RF Engineers, SS7, Business Object, Technical writers, Presales consultants etc.

#### RGI

Team Lead - Recruitment September 2004 - April 2008 (3 years 8 months)

Recruiter -> Sr. Recruiter -> Team Lead - Recruitment.

# Education

Andhra University

B Com, Commerce · (1999 - 2002)